So, in the last lecture I explained that React is all about components and that components are awesome.
W ostatnim wykadzie wyjaniem, e w React chodzi wycznie o komponenty, a komponenty s niesamowite.
Let's actually see this on a real web page. Here's reactjs.org,
Zobaczmy to na prawdziwej stronie internetowej. Oto reactjs. org, ktra
which is the official web page
jest oficjaln stron
of the React team.
zespou React.
If we have a look at it, it is actually built with React (of course).
Jeli spojrzymy na to, jest on zbudowany z React (oczywicie).
This looks like a normal web page and it is; but we can split this up into components.
Wyglda to jak normalna strona internetowa i jest; ale moemy podzieli to na komponenty.
We've got this Header component and in there we've got these Single Navigation Item components.
Mamy ten komponent Header, a tam mamy elementy pojedynczego elementu nawigacyjnego.
We've got this Starting Image/Call-To-Action component here and we've got all our elements down here
Mamy tutaj komponent Obraz pocztkowy / wezwanie do dziaania, a tutaj mamy wszystkie nasze elementy, w ktrych
where they advertise React and what it is about. We see more components here like these Image Code Snippet
reklamuj React i o czym jest mowa. Widzimy tutaj wicej komponentw, takich jak komponenty Fragment kodu
components with some descriptions to the left of them.
obrazu z niektrymi opisami po lewej stronie.
All these things are basically building blocks which we can of course easily consider as reusable pieces
Wszystkie te rzeczy to w zasadzie bloki konstrukcyjne, ktre oczywicie moemy z atwoci uzna za elementy
and actually they are reusing this element here.
wielokrotnego uytku i faktycznie ponownie uywaj tego elementu.
We've got one element here and then the same element with different content being used below it.
Mamy tutaj jeden element, a nastpnie ten sam element z inn zawartoci pod nim.
Now, you can hard-code all this with just HTML, JavaScript and CSS, but then you will
Teraz moesz zakodowa to wszystko za pomoc kodu HTML, JavaScript i CSS, ale
have to repeat your code over and over again. Here, with components,  you build your own HTML elements,
wtedy bdziesz musia wielokrotnie powtarza swj kod. Tutaj, z komponentami, budujesz wasne elementy HTML, by
so to say, and then you just reuse those elements.
tak rzec, a nastpnie ponownie je wykorzystasz.
Behind the scenes, this HTML element has all this content already inside of it and we'll see this
Za kulisami ten element HTML zawiera ju ca zawarto, a my zobaczymy to
in detail in a second.
szczegowo w cigu sekundy.
Another good example would be Udemy. Here on the Udemy page where I searched for Vue.js
Innym dobrym przykadem byby Udemy. Tutaj na stronie Udemy, gdzie szukaem Vue. js (alternatywa dla
(an alternative to React),
React), widzimy, e
we see there are a lot of components too.
jest te wiele komponentw.
We've got this whole Header with the Search Bar component.
Mamy cay nagwek ze skadnikiem Search Bar.
We've got this Search Results Summary component that allows us to filter the search results
Mamy ten podsumowanie podsumowania wynikw wyszukiwania, ktry pozwala nam filtrowa wyniki wyszukiwania, a my
and we also have the search results themselves.
take sami mamy wyniki wyszukiwania.
We've got reused List Item components here.
Mamy tutaj ponownie wykorzystane elementy listy elementw.
Each of them has an image and a different title,
Kady z nich ma obraz i inny
but in the core they are all the same.
tytu, ale w rdzeniu wszystkie s takie same.
They all have the same structure
Wszystkie maj t sam
and Udemy also uses a JavaScript framework to achieve this and to allow for easier development and,
struktur, a Udemy wykorzystuje take framework JavaScript do osignicia tego celu i umoliwia atwiejszy rozwj, a
this is important,
to jest wane,
maintaining and updating this page.
utrzymanie i aktualizowanie tej strony.
So this is why components are awesome and why we as a developer probably want to use components and that
To dlatego komponenty s niesamowite i dlaczego my, jako programista, prawdopodobnie chcemy korzysta z komponentw i
is why React is all about components.
dlatego w React chodzi wycznie o komponenty.